本视频由Brilliant赞助
This video is supported by Brilliant.
2012年夏天 太空叉打算把火箭发射业务拓展到佛罗里达州之外
In the summer of 2012, SpaceX were looking to expand their rocket launching business outside of Florida.
当时 他们只发射过几次猎鹰九号火箭
At the time, the company had only flown their Falcon 9 rocket a handful of times.
但随着发射档期越来越满 他们更迫切地需要一个新发射场来满足需求
But with a rapidly increasing launch schedule, an additional launch site was required to meet their needs.
他们开始关注德克萨斯州一个叫Boca Chica的小镇
They started looking at a small village in Texas called Boca Chica
在那里 他们可以建造私有的太空港
where they could start building their own private spaceport.
BC是卡梅伦县的一个小社区 只有35栋房子
Boca Chica is a tiny community in Cameron County, made up of just 35 houses.
这里有海景房 还远离文明的喧嚣
For years, it has been the dream spot for retirees and vacationers,
让这里在多年来一直都是退休人员和度假者的梦想之地
with waterfront properties - far away from civilization.
村子里就在这样一片没有人烟的安宁之地，
The village is located on such a quiet and untouched peace of land
必须用卡车每月一次送水进社区
that water must be trucked into the community once a month.
像买菜这些基本的跑腿 则要通勤40分钟到最近的Brownsville市
Basic errands like grocery shopping requires a 40 minute commute into the nearest city of Brownsville.
于是问题来了
This raises the question,
为什么太空叉会选择这样一个贫穷而荒凉的地方开始建设他们未来的太空港？
why would SpaceX choose such a poor and desolate part of the country to start building their future spaceport?
尽管这里缺乏很多基础设施与熟练劳动力
Despite the lack of basic infrastructure or a skilled workforce,
BC镇仍然有很多太空叉所需要的优点
the quiet town of Boca Chica actually had a lot to offer SpaceX.
除了大量的廉价土地和距离很近的出海口以外
Along with the abundance of cheap land and nearby access to the sea,
BC镇的人口密度也很低
Boca Chica also had a low population density,
使其成为发射 着陆火箭的绝佳地点
making it the perfect location to launch and land rockets.
德州政府还给了他们1500万美元 资助他们建造太空港
The state of Texas was also offering a $15 million incentive for them to build their spaceport in Texas.
因此 太空叉选择在BC镇建造他们未来的太空港 并于2014年破土动工
So SpaceX chose Boca Chica as their future spaceport and broke ground in 2014.
虽然猎鹰九号火箭的发射计划达到了历史最高点
Although the Falcon 9's launch schedule was at an all time high,
但几年过去 BC镇的发射场却没有任何建设进展
several years went by without any construction at the site.
在当时
By this point,
多方猜测太空叉改变了他们在BC镇建太空港的想法
many assumed that SpaceX had changed their mind about building their new spaceport in Boca Chica.
殊不知 BC镇的生活即将永远被改变
But life in the little town of Boca Chica was about to change forever.
2018年12月 一位当地居民分享了一张太空叉工地新“建筑”的图片
In December 2018, a local resident shared an image of a new structure at the SpaceX site.
图片迅速在航天爱好者圈子里传开
These images quickly spread around the space community
许多人猜测这个“建筑”可能是太空叉开始建造的Starship火箭
and many suggested that the structure could in fact be the beginnings of SpaceX's new Starship rocket.
在当时不少人觉得这猜想就离谱
At the time, this seemed like a crazy theory
更多人认为这单纯是工地新造的水塔
and most people assumed that this was simply a new water tower being built for the site.
但在一轮又一轮的猜测后
But after rounds of speculation,
太空叉终于透露 这玩意就是正在建造的Starhopper火箭
SpaceX revealed that this structure really was the beginnings of a rocket called "Starhopper"
——Starship的早期测试箭
- designed as an early test bed for Starship.
时间过去几个月 太空叉刷屏的消息越来越多
As the months went on, SpaceX's presence in the community grew
他们也终于准备好测试Starhopper了
and soon they were ready to test Starhopper.
在当地居民对他们一举一动的记录下
With local residents documenting every move,
Starhopper终于带来了一次独一无二的飞行表演
Starhopper took to the sky in a spectacular show,
并用其自身动力成功着陆
coming back down to land under its own propulsion.
虽然这次测试对太空叉来说是一项重大成就，但也不是一帆风顺
While this test was a major achievement for SpaceX, it didn't come without its disturbances.
在测试中 BC镇的居民需要离开房屋 避免因玻璃被震坏而受伤
During the test, residents had to remain outside of their homes to avoid getting injured by shattering windows.
又过了几周
As the weeks went on,
太空叉意识到 他们无法在不给居民带来危险的情况下扩大测试规模
it was clear that SpaceX couldn't increase the scale of their tests without putting the residents in danger.
所以太空叉开始了他们的 小镇收购计划
So SpaceX began the process of buying out the entire town
他们致函小镇居民 表示愿意以三倍市场价收购房屋
and sent letters to residents offering to buy their house for three times the market value.
虽然的确有很多居民接受了提议
Although many residents accepted the offer,
但很多人会拒绝太空叉出的高价 拒绝放弃他们梦想中的生活
many understandably declined and refused to give up their dream life
这也是可以理解的
to a company that could easily offer so much more.
以每栋资产均价8万美元来算
With an average property value of around $80,000,
太空叉收购全部房屋要花850万美元
SpaceX would have spent at least $8.5 million to buyout every house.
但对于那些被迫搬走的居民来说
But for the residents that were being pressured to move,
即使是三倍的高价也不足以让他们在其他地方找到类似的房子
even a triple-value offer wouldn't be enough to find a similar home in a different location.
虽然太空叉无权把居民赶走 但县政府有
While SpaceX doesn't have the right to kick residents out of their homes, the County does.
而且虽然县政府也不愿意把居民赶走
And while the County wants to avoid evicting people from their homes,
但摆在县政府面前的 是一个方兴未艾的产业机遇
they have an opportunity to create a thriving industry
一个可以为全国经济最萧条地区之一提供高薪工作的机遇
and provide high paying jobs to one of the most economically depressed regions of the country.
这也正是征用权的意义所在
This is where eminent domain comes in.
德州法律规定
Texas law states that
"私人财产只能由政府或经授权的私人企业征用"
"private property may only be taken by a government or private entity that is authorized to do so,"
这意味着卡梅伦县可以给予太空叉征用财产的权利
meaning that Cameron County could give SpaceX the right to seize the properties.
然而 法律还规定
However, these legal requirements also state that
征用任何财产的目的必须是有利于公众的
seizing any property must only occur for a purpose that benefits the general public.
虽然德州政府不可能为私人企业的利益而提供征用权
While Texas does not allow eminent domain for the benefit of private landowners,
但太空叉还有一个选择 就是把土地交给政府
there is an alternative which would involve SpaceX giving the land over to the government.
但这并不是太空叉的理想选择
This would not be ideal for SpaceX
因为他们将有失去对第一个私人太空港的控制权的风险
since they would risk losing control over their first privately owned spaceport.
因此太空叉决定延长截止日期 并为一些剩余的居民提高报价
SpaceX decided to extend their deadline and increase offers for some of the remaining residents.
还会对一些居民的房屋进行重新估值
Some residents were able to get their homes reevaluated
因为太空叉之前没有把居民失业的损失统计进去
since SpaceX hadn't taken into account the loss of business for residents
而有些居民会把自己的房屋改造成AirBnB之类的民宿
that were using their homes as an AirBnB.
到了三月 还有7栋房屋没有卖给太空叉
As of March, seven houses remain unsold to SpaceX
谈判可能还将继续下去
and the negotiations could continue to go on for much longer.
太空叉很可能会倾尽全力购买剩余的资产
SpaceX will likely do everything they can to purchase the remaining properties
并最终将小镇变成自家的工厂
and claim the village to themselves.
太空叉最近雇佣了数百名新工人 打造了一条24小时不间断的生产线
SpaceX recently hired hundreds of new workers to create a constant 24 hour production line.
虽然BC镇的居民基本上被迫放弃了他们的梦想生活
Although the residents of Boca Chica were essentially forced to give up their dream life,
但希望这将是太空叉试图为人类创造的激动人心的未来的重要牺牲
it will hopefully be an important sacrifice for the exciting future
that SpaceX are trying to create for everyone.
Thanks to Brilliant for sponsoring this episode of Primal Space.
There are multiple ways to learn about a topic on the internet -
but the way Brilliant teaches you to think critically about a problem
and truly understand it is unique.
If you liked this video, you probably have an interest in things like space, science, math and engineering.
In that case, Brilliant has you covered.
Brilliant is a problem solving website
with a wide range of interactive courses
that break complex topics down into smaller and more understandable chunks.
Brilliant isn't just about memorizing facts and formulas,
it's about developing a deep understanding of how and why things work.
So you can apply them to everyday life.
To support the channel and learn more about Brilliant, visit brilliant.
org/primalspace The first 200 people to sign up will get 20% off the yearly subscription
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.